Among the books that came out recently, there is a
book titled “An Attitude to Life that Moves On Without Swaying.” The
gist of the children’s book is that a person must
change. If they don’t change, they cannot. This book
greatly emphasizes the importance of change.
On the cover of this book,
there was this phrase: If you want to live a better life,
break yourself. Oh, this really
hit home. If you want to live a better life,
break yourself today. There was also this phrase on the cover: If
I change, everything
changes. It’s such an obvious idea, but
it’s such a basic story. If
I change in my family, my family
changes. If I change in my community, in the small group
attic, that community
changes, and it becomes the starting point for the church to change. This
book emphasizes this. In this book,
there is a part that emphasizes the necessity of change using the English word “sheet.” As
you may know, this
word “sheet” means to change a location or move.
The author uses this word and says
that “sheet”
refers to an attitude that changes me into a better person. He gives an
example while explaining this. When
a baby
is born, the first thing you do is cut the umbilical cord.
Why do you do that?
When a baby is in the mother's womb,
all the nutrients and elements necessary for life are
supplied through the excretion.
And also, breathing is also done through the
placenta. The fetus
receives oxygen from the mother's blood and
expels carbon dioxide. All of these things are
done through the placenta.
However, from the moment it is born on this earth, it can no longer
receive any more supplies from its mother.
So,
life begins by cutting off the excretion.
And also, what is 100% common in all of them? They
cry as soon as they are
born. So, if the baby doesn't cry when they are born, they
make them cry by hitting their buttocks. There is also a meaning to this. The reason
why the baby has to cry that initial sound is
because
air enters the space between the vocal cords that has never been used before,
creating a friction sound. This is the
first time for babies. So,
now that the umbilical cord is cut, breathing,
inhaling oxygen,
exhaling carbon dioxide, all of these things must be
done in a different way to live. So,
humans
have this shift from the time they are born.  They
used the expression “born”. When I
read a book explaining this principle, it said that if you cut off the old to
live a new life in the new world, it’s the
same spiritually. I
thought that
believing in Jesus
means something like this. Some people say, “
I become a registered member of a sports center during the week and
exercise, and
in the evening, I enroll in an English academy and
learn English, and now it’s Sunday. I
go to church on Sunday and
attend a service, and that’s not it.”
Some people misunderstand that this is what a life of faith is.
Being born again is not about registering at a health club and
exercising. A
life of faith is being born again.
New life is being granted.
So if we say that we believe in Jesus, we
have to cut off the strings of our way of life that has relied on our own strength and looked at the world. We have to block
all the channels that have been effective in our way of living,
and now we
recognize that we are beings who can receive supplies from God and
live. This is a
life of faith. Today, as
I meditated on verse 6 of Psalm 23,
I received many messages from this short verse. I studied it a lot and
enjoyed grace during the week. It
all started with the beginning of Psalm 23.
Don't you do this? Verse 1
says, "He is my shepherd; I shall not want."
This is the shift. If we do what the book says, this is the
transformation. When you read this verse, you may think, "Oh,
what did I need to fill up to be satisfied in the past?
Oh, I need to have money in my bank account to
eat and live until I die,
and I need to have a job that I can be recognized for,
and I need to be respected by people to some
extent. I live in a world that keeps singing that I need to have these things
filled up so that I don't lack anything in life." But
now that I know Jesus,
we are now realizing that this is not the case.
That's why David says, "Because the Lord
is my shepherd, I shall
not want anything." David begins his words
by saying this, and in verse 6, he concludes his words with
this: "Goodness and
mercy shall surely follow me all my days, and I will dwell
in the house of the Lord forever."
He talks about the way of life. This
week, I will speak about the sentence, "Goodness and
mercy shall surely follow me all my days, and
I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever." Next week, at the end, I will say this one sentence, "I
will dwell in the house of the Lord forever." I will preach this next
week, and Psalm 23.
It's organized. In this sense, I
hope that today, with the first part of verse 6 of chapter 23, I and you will experience a change in life. The decision to cut the umbilical cord
will occur, and I will no longer be someone who relies on something of my own and
lives according to the world's order,
but a person who
is now Jehovah my shepherd, and I will
live a
life where I rely on Him and live with what He provides. I hope that
you will become saints of faith like this.
So
I came up with this title.
Two words to remember for a shift in life. You need
to remember these two words. The
first word is goodness. Goodness. I will
read verse 6 again.
Goodness and mercy will surely follow me all my life.
The goodness mentioned here is the
word Tov in Hebrew.
Many of you may have heard of Tov. This word Tov is
one of the very first words in the Bible.
It came from the process of creating heaven and earth. Let me
read it to you. It
is Genesis 1:1, which is at the very beginning of the Bible. In the beginning,
God created the heavens and the earth.
The Bible begins with God's declaration. It's
not that monkeys evolved
or anything like that, but that God
created with a purpose and intention. This is the declaration of the Bible.
In the beginning, God
created the heavens and the earth. And now the
content is verse 2. The earth was formless and
empty, and darkness
was over the face of the deep. And the Spirit of God was hovering over the face of the waters. And
God said, "Let there be
light." And there was light. And God said, "It
is good."
And on the second day,
God created it like this. And in conclusion,
God saw that it was good. On the third day,
it was good. So if you look at the Bible, it goes
on and on from the very beginning.
So, everyone,
the goodness and kindness of my life will
surely follow me.
How should we meditate
on this goodness? When God created the heavens and the earth, it means that it was good.
Oh, God, I used good materials.
Oh, this is
not like this. Here, Tov does not mean that God
created it with a purpose. It
was created according to His intention.
This does not mean that Tov was well made.
Of course, that is implied,
but it is said that
God created it well according to His intention.  It
was good to see, so that's why we who believed in Jesus
came here by following the goodness of God. It's not goodness in the sense that I
became rich, I lived well, I
became famous.
When God sent me to this earth,
living a life according to the will of God is
goodness. So, in Ephesians 2:10, it
says that we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works. Even if we cook rice, the life that
God intended for us to
live
is a successful life.
I told you all about a young man who was pessimistic about his
life and thought that
all that was left for him to do was to die.
He had actually attempted
suicide again just before I met him, but
it didn't work out. When I
met him, I was
very worried. It
was
so heartbreaking.
How
could we know the details? He had been living alone for a long time, isolated from his parents.
Since he lived alone, I listened to his brother's story for an hour.
I
see that you are anxious. You are alone when you get home. I wonder if even if I encourage you for an hour, pat you on the back, and pray for you, will the fundamental problem be solved. I am very worried about that, so I spoke to the young man. I see that you live alone now, so it
seems that you need some help.
So if you allow me,
I would like to explain this content well during the sermon on Sunday and
find someone who can help our brother. Is that okay?
When I talk about someone's personal story, I usually
get permission to talk about serious stories. I asked if
I could talk about you,
and then suddenly this
person said, "I can reveal my name. I want you to
help me find that everything is okay in my brother's heart. I
think it just came out because I was so desperate." That was in September of last
year. Do you remember? Pastors who still remember what I preached last year
really hate that kind of thing. That's
because even if I repeat the sermon I gave last week as if it was the first time,
our pastor
likes new words, and he remembers what I said last year.
What should I do? That happened.
So thankfully, after that, the
counselor and various
people  He contacted me to help me, and
among them, a
male deacon who is currently a Sunday school teacher at our church
contacted me. Pastor, can I help that young man?
So I
connected him. And then I had
n’t heard from him since then, so I
had forgotten about him, but he contacted me a while ago. To be
honest, I was anxious. Whether it
was no news or a brother contacting me, I wondered if he was
having any more difficulties. When I
met him carefully, I thought, “Oh, I
can’t have that cold that day.”
There was a young man sitting there who had completely changed. At first, I didn’t know. I
didn’t know. I didn’t
recognize him. Wow, it’s
so important to change your impression. When I first met him,
he was so dark and gloomy and
had no energy, and his voice was
like a dying voice.
But he had such a
bright expression and such a good impression. When he spoke with such a bright expression,
I was so happy.
So I thought, “Oh, this is a good thing.”
After hearing his story,
after I preached, some
people started praying for him and I
connected him with him.
Among them, this man who is now a Sunday school teacher  I
met the deacon, and this was a blessing of meeting him.
The deacon
bought me meals and regularly
gave me gifts, although I don’t know, and I
think he gave me various things. I wanted to tell him that I had changed after meeting that good teacher,
so we talked for an hour, and he
thankfully prepared a small gift and
put a letter in it.
So I asked him what he should
give me as a gift. He said, “What’s wrong with giving gifts? It’s not
that I’m good at it. It’s that I
have some free time.” When
I came in with the letter and read it, he said, “
I’ve been taking that letter
out a lot lately.
Listen to the beginning. Pastor, I’m the brother who
received great grace from you since September 13th.
From that time, I was able to endure until I could write this thank-you letter through the counseling teacher you visited
and the intercessory prayers you didn’t have.
Pastor,
I’m enjoying the peace and joy that the Lord gives me now. I’m
no longer afraid of tomorrow.
Many things have happened since I met the pastor, but I
let go of the stability and meaning that the world gave me that I was obsessed with. The umbilical
cord that I mentioned earlier  It's a story of cutting off the line. It's a story of cutting off
the line that relied on the world that led this brother to the impulses that only brought despair, discouragement, and frustration. I really wanted to tell you that the world changed when
I
let go of the stability and meaning that the world that I was obsessed with gave me.
Pastor, I finally
believe and rely on the Lord that He is a merciful and truly loving God.
When I read the Word, I feel the Word touching my heart
every day. Every time, I see what I have to do and the
meaning of my life. When I
asked what happened to my brother right now, it
was exactly as I said earlier. Being guided by goodness
does not mean becoming rich, living well, and being famous. It's because this brother realized the meaning of life
and began to find out what kind of meaning God gave him when He sent him to this earth, and he
became motivated.
So how did this brother come to
pursue the meaning of life like this? I think I
saw a sample of what a real adult is in that Sunday school teacher, that deacon. He
encouraged and supported this brother with all his heart and
soul, and he always
gave homework when they parted ways. He said, "Read the four gospels of the Bible once."
And there, Jesus said,  Meditate on the things Jesus did on earth.
Organize this. This
brother is a good brother. He
keeps his promises well. What's more, an
adult I am so grateful for came to me and
gave me such grace, so I
did that. While this brother was talking, he
kept reading all the things Jesus did in the Four Gospels,
and something changed. This
brother met me and told me this story.
His mentor told him
to meditate on the things Jesus did while reading the Four Gospels. So he
did that, and in the process, he
began to recall the good things God had intervened in him. He
said that when he was young, he was
bullied at school.
He was bullied, and at that time, God
gave him strength.
Listen to the next part of the letter. I thought my past was
full of suffering, but as I did that, I
discovered that I had not been grateful for the things God had done for me in the past and had left.
What this means is that when I
met him, I despaired, and the
reason I resented God
was because God had abandoned me. God
abandoned me, and so I
He said that there was nothing left to do, but the mentor
teacher and deacon told him to read the four gospels and
meditate on what Jesus did, and
something amazing happened. As he read and
meditated on them, he began to recall things that he had forgotten about when
God was with him during difficult times. There
is an expression like this. Among the contents, there
is this. At first, as he discovered one, two, three, and
eight, it
seemed endless. And he
could not help but admit that God had given him endless opportunities.
This means that God’s
work and goodness were with him.
Also, when he was bullied at school,
God had opened up to him. Also, when he was serving in the military, I forgot what happened and couldn’t remember, but he remembered that God had intervened in his life when he was going through difficult times.
And this
brother was so moved by God’s
endless intervention as he discovered one, two, three, and eight things. At the
end of the letter, he
confessed like this.
Pastor, now I
can no longer praise the Lord who is no longer a reward.
As you know, it is such a great joy and honor to believe in the Lord and
gain new strength every day.
Now
my only hope is
not to let go of the Lord's hand that I have barely grasped again, and to
help other souls in need and
give glory to the Lord.
The doubts in this brother's life are
good. That goodness is. No matter what kind of
circumstances I live in, living the way God intended
when He created me and sent me to this earth is
good.
Wasn't it the same for Joseph? If we
consider hardships, Joseph was like his
brothers. He was threatened with death by his half-brother,
sold to another country, and
unjustly imprisoned. But
everyone, read the Bible. There is
no trace of Joseph. How was this possible
? The answer is in the famous words he said to his brothers after he had lived his entire life and
overcome it.
Genesis 50:20
says this to the brothers who sold him. "You
intended to harm me, but God intended it for
good. Here is the
good. You sold me because you hated me,
but in that sold life, you
found the life that God intended and planned through you, so
it did not become despair, but rather became material and
motivation.
Joseph's life is not
comparable to mine, but
the principle is the same. I also
felt suicidal in my early 20s. It was
n't as severe as my brother's.
I just wanted to die.
And it didn't seem like this tunnel would ever end. When in the world would my
English suddenly improve in a thousand years? Would my deceased
father suddenly come back to life and pay for my tuition? Would
someone suddenly sponsor me by giving me a few thousand dollars for my
tuition
? That's why I wanted to die. Isn't this
endless tunnel a cave
? But what came to my mind when this strange thing
happened
was,
God went through this difficult process, and
now I have to help someone who is having a hard time. If
I die because it's hard,
who will
help that person? I was only two years old at the time.
Isn't that a funny story?
Who am I to help right now? I'm going
to die. But God, I
didn't even know that Ephesians 2:10 says, "For we are the workmanship of God, created
in Christ Jesus to do good works." I
didn't even know that such a verse existed. I was ignorant and didn't even know that such a verse existed.
God guided me with goodness,
so I thought, I
have to live. If I die,
what will happen to the person I have to help? That’s how
I
held on, but after meeting this brother,
isn’t that the thought I had when I was two years old coming true? If I had
n’t met this brother and died and disappeared,
who would have connected this brother to that deacon?
I’m telling you again that God’s
goodness is not in you eating well and living well.
Sometimes you are unjustly
put in prison, sometimes you are unjustly
sold to your brothers, and your heart is traded, and
in the process, you
try and strive to find God’s goodness.
This is the appearance of believers, and that’s
where their strength comes from. That’s why
I make it funny. It’s true.
Jusasil. Jusasil is a gathering of people who practice the love of the Lord. My
seniors in faith at my university in Korea planted that dream in me, so
I created Jusasil.
That’s why I
don’t have enough money in my bank account to eat and die, but I recruited members and I
said, “Let’s help our weak neighbors, the
role model of weak neighbors.”
That’s why
Jusasil was created when I was 10,000 years old.  I had
no organization, so I had it for a while and it
disappeared. That main fact is gone,
but isn't that spirit still continuing? I want this spirit to continue somehow through our church in Bundang. Are
you
passing through a valley where the shadow of death is falling? You have to
find God's goodness there.
What does God want from me in this process?
When I was two years old, I was young and foolish. I thought, "If I
die like this, what will happen to
the person I have to help when I get out of this tunnel?" That
ridiculous thought was
planted in a two-year-old because God
was guiding me with goodness.
So today, I want you to remember the
word Tov-i-To, the goodness of my life.
On the other hand,
there is a second word that we have to remember in order for our lives to change, and that
is kindness. I will read verse 6 and explain this kindness. My
goodness and kindness
will surely follow me all my life. The kindness mentioned here
is Hed in Hebrew. You may have heard this before. This
Hesed
means rain, love, kindness.
In the Old Testament,
Hesed is a word used to describe the character of God.
God  The heart that pities your people
is the head. What is David confessing now
? What
did that Hesed say?
It is unconditional love. When David looked back on his deep life,
there was a moment when he committed a heinous act. He committed murder, got a
married woman pregnant, and
arranged a business
to take that man's loyalty. Who is this David who
committed such heinous acts by murdering that man and committing
such heinous acts
? But did
n't God embrace him with His love?
Repentance is important when you repent.
Let me trace it like this.
If David wrote Psalm 23 while reflecting on his past life, I think he would have cried at this part. I
guess it's because
goodness and the love of Hesed
have followed me throughout my life that
I was forgiven and given a chance to stand up again.
The
book I introduced earlier, an attitude toward life that moves forward without wavering,
says that a
transformation into a better person is necessary, but
there are human emotions that hinder this.
Why do we live such a life?  Since the shift
doesn't happen well, I asked
what emotions are interfering with it.
There are several. First, anxiety
holds back our change. I'll explain it all.
Next is depression. Depression
interferes with our shift to a better life. Next is
burnout, exhaustion, and
then low self-esteem. I
'm telling you that you have to stop being kicked out.
In fact, isn't the system of life in this era a
structure that mass-produces four things?
In our era today, we are anxious even when we do nothing. We are
anxious when we rest. We
are anxious when we get up and lie down. We wake up in the morning and
start the day with anxiety before it even starts.
That's the structure.
Today's era is depressing. Smartphones
have come out and we are even more depressed.
The news we look at every day makes us depressed. It
causes anger. It's burnout. And this
era keeps destroying our self-esteem.
In the old days,
when there were no smartphones,
no one knew who was living so well.
I lived in a poor neighborhood.
Even though the whole world was poor, I was born in a
neighborhood that was like that, but I guess the whole
world lives like this.  I
thought I would go to the podium every day and drink and
live like that. I
can't name people. I drank so much coal briquette gas that I
had no complaints. Because of that, I
didn't have any difficulties in my heart. But
now that smartphones have broken my self-esteem,
people
keep posting about how great I am and the more I travel around the world, the more
depressed I become.
You guys
need to cut that umbilical cord. God doesn't evaluate people by those
things, and Hesed, who unconditionally
forgives and loves those who don't deserve it,
will surely follow me all my life. But there's
one thing you need to remember about Hesed. As
I said earlier,
in the Old Testament, Hesed is God's character.
So when Hesed reveals God's character, the
word Se appears, and
there are times when this word is used toward humans.
A representative example is Micah 6:8. You
have shown me, O man, what is good. What does the LORD require of me
but to do justice and
to love kindness? This Hesed is what God
requires. Hesed Edu
Mentor Deacon  That girl, when she met me, she
kept
calling me uncle. When I met that uncle,
that uncle
told me to read the Four Gospels and
I corrected him. That mentor
deacon said that. So that person said that
uncle, my uncle, did that. I
thought about it. If that
deacon had a great gift of teaching and
met this young man and suddenly said, “
Now, read this. You, I believe in Jesus. I
can commit suicide. No. I can’t commit suicide.
Don’t think like that.” If he
had approached
him like that, what would have happened? That deacon
didn’t approach this brother like that. He approached him in threes.
For no reason, he
bought our young man a very delicious meal for the first time. He may
have given him a gift, although I don’t know. He may
have even given him pocket money.
He showed this brother the love of Hesed with all his heart. Isn’t
it power to recommend that he read the Four Gospels with that love
? Today, I hope that
God’s unconditional love, Hesed, will
be enjoyed a lot. And we must remember the
Lord’s words that we must also give it.  Let's
take a look at Genesis 39:5, which you all know.
From the time he made Joseph in charge of his house and all that he had, you
must listen carefully to this. The Lord
blessed Joseph's house for Joseph's sake. If
I read it like this,
this is the world's perspective that still can't be kicked out, but the
perspective of God in the Bible is this.
From the time he made Joseph in charge of his house and all that he had, then
look next. The Lord
blessed Joseph's house.
You guys are just watching this because it's someone else's story, but think about
it as your own story right now. If
God said
to me, for example, I live
in room 102 of building 10, I'm a pastor, and
I want to bless you for your hard work. I
want you to bless me and make your mother do well, then
would you all say, Hallelujah? Oh,
God, I am. If God said to you,
I will bless you and make your
neighbor do well, you might say, "I
can't believe in a God like this."
But
you guys, this is the principle of the Bible. You know what I often
say? I
didn't commit suicide when I was 2 years old.  I hope that this work of persevering and overcoming will
become a gift to someone from God.
Amen.
Just preaching on Sundays and
going to the wedding hall and all that kind of stuff
doesn't do the job of a pastor. I
really want my life to be a life that provides gifts to you,
even though it is so insignificant and small.
This
is the spirit of Hesed. You
must remember two things. First, we
need a shift in our lives, a change in our lives, and
the first ingredient is Tobu.
In order to find the meaning that God created me, I
can find even a valley where the shadow of death is cast over me.
I was able to find it.
Then the second
word is the goodness and mercy of my life, Hesed.
Hesed. So, first of all, I hope that you will
enjoy the unconditional love of Hesed given to those who are not worthy of it and live a
beautiful life that lets it flow.
Especially these days, we
need to seek the love of Hesed for our country. I have posted some
prayer topics for this country on the homepage.
Please
take a good look at the contents. Originally, I
was going to print them out and give them to you. Please
look at the homepage, print them out yourself, and
pray for this country. Now is the
time when we need God's Hesed.
God, now.  In
this age where various wounds are constantly being produced, only God knows
whether you are right or I am right. Let's
reserve judgment and pray
together that God will have pity on our country even when something
more desperate than this
happened, with God's love of Hesed.
That's why I love the national anthem so much.
Isn't it because God protected us that our country has come this far?
Everyone, you and I have experienced this revival first for that reason, so
I am touched. I am
not qualified to preach, but
God is preaching, but I still
can't make excuses. God's love of Hesed has
allowed me to stand here.
Today, as we
remember this word, let's
read Matthew 5:7 and end our message.
Blessed are the merciful, for
they will be shown mercy. It
is a virtuous cycle. If I
pour out the love of Hesed that I received onto someone,
God will be pleased with it and
return it to me with a greater Hesed. I think that this player of love is the alternative that
the Lord gives us today to heal this age.
Today's
word is for me and you to shift our lives.  Let's
sing this praise song together, hoping that it will be those two words that bring us. Do not
fear anything, the Lord my God protects you. Do
not be surprised, do not be afraid.
Who will protect us next?
The Lord protects me. I
cut the string that relied on the world and turned toward the world, and
now, God, I
want to go forward relying on you. Let's sing this praise song together. Do
not fear anything, do
not be afraid of anything, the Lord my
God protects you. He protects you. You are my
good self. Do not be
surprised, do not be afraid, do not be afraid. Who will
protect you? The Lord
protects me. I confess once more. Do not
fear anything.
The system of this world
drives us into fear, but the Lord my
God protects you. He
protects you. Do not be surprised, do not be afraid. Do not be afraid. I
declare with my lips. The Lord
protects me. He
protects me. My life's journey. My heart is
strong.
Remember at that time. The Lord
protects me. The rough waves of the world may
crash down. Even
at that moment, remember.
The Lord protects me.
Yes, the Lord is my
mountain, my cold.
The Lord is
mine, the
Lord is mine.
The Lord is my hope. The Lord is my
cow. My strength, Jehovah, Jehovah. Let's
sing once again. Do
not fear anything,
nothing.  Do not be afraid, the Lord my God
protects you. The
Lord
protects me. Do not be afraid, do not be
afraid, do not be afraid. Who protects me and you?
The Lord protects me. Even
if my heart is tired and worn out,
Even if my heart is tired and worn out,
You protect me.
The Lord who
protects me, I declare once with faith.
The Lord is my
fortress,
ten. The
Lord is my fortress, ten. The Lord is my hope,
the Lord is my
hope, my strength, the strength of Jehovah.
Rise up and my heart is tired and worn out, Even if my heart is tired and worn out, My
heart is strengthened. At every moment, ten. The cold waves
of the world
will blow.
At every moment before that,
declare. The Lord protects me.
The Lord is my fortress, the Lord is my cold. The Lord is my
fortress, the
Lord is my
hope, my cow, Jehovah my strength,
Jehovah my strength.
Today, I will pray for you. The
living God, the Father, for
we are his workmanship, created
in Christ Jesus to good works.
Surely goodness and mercy will follow me all the days of my life.
I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
God, as the years pass and all my days are numbered,
When we look back on our lives,
if we can only confess like this Psalm 23:6,
what more
could we ask for in our lives? Even though
there were times when we passed through the valley where the shadow of death hung over us, and moments when we suffered from unjustly false accusations like Joseph and suffered from wounds that we could not imagine, and times when life was so hard that
we felt the urge to give up when we were young,
Jehovah intervened in my life through all of those processes, and
my life was a life where His goodness and
mercy never left me, and
when we confess, I believe that all of
our pains will
become crowns before the Lord. Please help me endure and live this
week with the strength that the word given today brings, and
God, sometimes,
just like that young man, I was healed and recovered
because of the people around me who were so good in their faith in the Lord, and
Lord, we too can become gifts to someone. If
I participate in the attic, I
believe that this goal, where someone gains strength because of me, is in the goodness of God that God gives, and
help us to dream of such a life. This week,
with the strength of the word given today,  Please guide me
to a beautiful week of perseverance and victory.